[
    {
        "question": "The full form of RDBMS is?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The full form of RDBMS is Relational Database Management System.",
        "options": [
            "Relational Database Management System",
            "Relational Database Management Services",
            "Relational Database Managerial Services",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the property of transaction that protects data from system failure?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The property “Durability” protects the data from system failure.",
        "options": [
            "Atomicity",
            "Isolation",
            "Consistency",
            "Durability"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is preserved in the execution of transactions in isolation?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Consistency is preserved in the execution of transactions in isolations.",
        "options": [
            "Atomicity",
            "Isolation",
            "Consistency",
            "Durability"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the lowest level of abstraction that describes how the data are actually stored?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The physical level of abstraction describes how the data are actually stored.",
        "options": [
            "Physical",
            "Abstract",
            "View",
            "User"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a relation in RDBMS?",
        "answer": "Explanation: In RDBMS, each table is also known as a relation.",
        "options": [
            "Table",
            "Key",
            "Data Types",
            "Row"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "“RDBMS has ACID properties”-Which of the following options is true about this statement?",
        "answer": "Explanation: ACID properties of RDBMS depend on the nature of data stored in the database.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False",
            "Depends on data in the RDBMS",
            "Maybe"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "During transaction before commit which of the following statement is done automatically in case of shutdown?",
        "answer": "Explanation: In case of a shutdown, Rollback is done automatically.",
        "options": [
            "Rollback",
            "Commit",
            "View",
            "Flashback"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "A relational database developer refers to a record as?",
        "answer": "Explanation: A record is also referred to as a Tuple.",
        "options": [
            "Relation",
            "Tuple",
            "Data",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The database is always expected to satisfy which predicate?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Assertion conditions are always expected to be satisfied by the database.",
        "options": [
            "Mandate",
            "Assertion",
            "Verify",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following can replace the below query?SELECT name, course_id  \n            FROM instructor, teaches  \n            WHERE instructor_ID= teaches_ID;",
        "answer": "Explanation: Join can be used to join 2 tables with the same attributes.",
        "options": [
            "Select name, course_id from instructor natural join teaches;",
            "Select name,course_id from teaches,instructor where instructor_id=course_id;",
            "Select name, course_id from instructor;",
            "Select course_id from instructor join teaches;"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The database system catalog stores what kind of information?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The database system catalog stores the number of tuples, number of blocks, size of a tuple in a relation, and the blocking factor in it as statistical data.",
        "options": [
            "Number of blocks",
            "Number of tuples",
            "Size of tuples mentioned",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The local variables that hold write operations are copied to the database work in which phase?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The local variables that hold write operations are copied to the database work in the Write Phase.",
        "options": [
            "Read Phase",
            "Write Phase",
            "Validation Phase",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the following query do?UPDATE student \nSET marks = marks * 1.20;",
        "answer": "Explanation: The UPDATE Command is used to edit a specific value in the tuple. The SET command sets the marks to a 20% greater value than the initial value.",
        "options": [
            "Increases marks by 120%",
            "Decreases marks by 20%",
            "Increase marks by 20%",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The relational model of RDBMS is concerned with?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The relation model consists of Data Structure, Data Manipulation, and Data Integrity.",
        "options": [
            "Data Structure",
            "Data Manipulation",
            "Data Integrity",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The attribute which is the primary key should have its values never?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The value of the primary key column should never have its values changed.",
        "options": [
            "Changed",
            "Dependent",
            "Independent",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The referential integrity constraint of a relational database can be specified with the help of?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Foreign Key specifies the referential integrity constraints of a relational database.",
        "options": [
            "Primary Key",
            "Secondary Key",
            "Foreign Key",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Minimal Superkeys are also called?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Minimal Superkeys are also called candidate keys.",
        "options": [
            "Primary Key",
            "Candidate Key",
            "Foreign Key",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of database design linked to the logical design is?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Database Schema is related to the logical design of a database.",
        "options": [
            "Database Schema",
            "Database Relation",
            "Database Entry",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are applications of dynamic hashing?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Dynamic Hashing allows for the accommodation of growth and shrinkage of the database as well as modification of the hash function.",
        "options": [
            "Accommodates growth and shrinkage of the database.",
            "Allows modification of the hash function.",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How can we delete entries in an RDBMS?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Delete command is used to delete entries from an RDBMS.",
        "options": [
            "Delete",
            "Insert",
            "Assign",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the correct foreign key constraint?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Referential Integrity is known as Foreign Key Constraint.",
        "options": [
            "Referential Integrity",
            "Entity Integrity",
            "Domain Integrity",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the query that is placed within a WHERE or HAVING clause of another query?",
        "answer": "Explanation: It is known as subquery.",
        "options": [
            "Multi Query",
            "Sub Query",
            "Super Query",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Modify operation is done after which operation?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Modify operation is performed after lookup.",
        "options": [
            "LookUp",
            "Insert",
            "Delete",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Date when inserted into a database should be of the format?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The correct format of inserting date is given in option C.",
        "options": [
            "YYYY-MM-DD",
            "“YYYY-MM-DD”",
            "‘YYYY-MM-DD’",
            "DD-MM-YYYY"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total view of a database is known as?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Total view of a database is known as the Conceptual view.",
        "options": [
            "Internal View",
            "Conceptual View",
            "Physical View",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "To select some particular columns, which of the following columns is used?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Projection is used to select some particular columns.",
        "options": [
            "PROJECTION",
            "SELECTION",
            "JOIN",
            "UNION"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is NTFS?",
        "answer": "Explanation: NTFS stands for New Technology File System.",
        "options": [
            "New Tree File System",
            "New Technology File System",
            "New Table File System",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are properties of entities?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Attributes are a property of entities.",
        "options": [
            "Table",
            "Attributes",
            "Groups",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following constraints does RDBMS checks before creating tables?",
        "answer": "Explanation: All of the above constraints are checked by RDBMS before creating tables.",
        "options": [
            "Not Null",
            "Primary Key",
            "Data Integrity",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "When is a domain called atomic?",
        "answer": "Explanation: A domain is called atomic when its elements are indivisible.",
        "options": [
            "Indivisible",
            "Divisible",
            "Constant",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Set of one or more attributes taken collectively to uniquely identify a record is called?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Super Key is a set of one or more attributes taken collectively to uniquely identify a record.",
        "options": [
            "Super Key",
            "Candidate Key",
            "Foreign Key",
            "Primary Key"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Language through which user requests data from a database is called?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The user requests data from a database using query language.",
        "options": [
            "Relational",
            "Assembly",
            "Query",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The union operation performs the set union of 2 ‘_______’ tables.",
        "answer": "Explanation: The union operation performs the set union of 2 ‘Similarly Structured’ tables.",
        "options": [
            "Similarly Structured",
            "Any 2 tables",
            "No union operation is defined as such",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The Select command is a part of what type of statement?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Select command is part of Data Manipulation Language or DML.",
        "options": [
            "DML",
            "DDL",
            "View",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of updates are not allowed in RDBMS?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Updates that violate the Integrity Constraints of a Database are not allowed in RDBMS.",
        "options": [
            "Integrity Constraints violations",
            "Authorization violations",
            "DDL Constraints violations",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of attributes in a relation is called its?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The number of attributes in a relation is called its Degree.",
        "options": [
            "Cardinality",
            "Degree",
            "Strength",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of Joins is a default in SQL?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Inner Joins are considered to be default in SQL.",
        "options": [
            "Inner",
            "Outer",
            "Self",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary key must be?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The primary key must be both unique and not null.",
        "options": [
            "Unique",
            "Not Null",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are examples of aggregate functions in SQL?",
        "answer": "Explanation: All of the above are examples of aggregate functions in SQL",
        "options": [
            "SUM",
            "MAX",
            "MIN",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "SQL update statements that can only be used in the set clause are called?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Scalar Subqueries can only be used in the set clause.",
        "options": [
            "Scalar Subqueries",
            "Conjoined Query",
            "Multiple Subqueries",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conditions allows a general predicate over the relations being joined?",
        "answer": "Explanation: The On condition allows a general predicate over the relations being joined.",
        "options": [
            "On",
            "Where",
            "Having",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum number of tables which can be joined with a join?",
        "answer": "Explanation: We can join multiple tables using joins.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "Multiple Tables can be joined"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How can we make a transaction permanent in the database?",
        "answer": "Explanation: We can make a transaction permanent in a database by committing the transaction.",
        "options": [
            "View",
            "Commit",
            "Rollback",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Maximum number of children of a B-tree of order N is?",
        "answer": "Explanation: A B-tree of order N is N.",
        "options": [
            "N / 2",
            "N - 1",
            "N",
            "N * N"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How is the ranking of queries done?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Ranking of queries is done using the Order By clause.",
        "options": [
            "Order By",
            "Group By",
            "Where",
            "Having"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the AS clause used for?",
        "answer": "Explanation: AS clause is used for rename.",
        "options": [
            "Projection",
            "Rename",
            "Select",
            "Union"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "OLAP stands for?",
        "answer": "Explanation: OLAP stands for Online Analytical Processing.",
        "options": [
            "Online Analytical Processing",
            "Online Analysis Processing",
            "Online Transaction Processing",
            "Online Aggregate Processing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of data can be modeled as dimensional and measure attributes?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Data that can be modeled as dimensional and measure attributes is called Multidimensional data.",
        "options": [
            "Multidimensional",
            "SingleDimsenional",
            "Measured",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Cross tabs in SQL are created using?",
        "answer": "Explanation: Cross Tabs are created in SQL using Slice.",
        "options": [
            "Slice",
            "Dice",
            "Pivot",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "A set of entities of same type that share same properties or attributes is called?",
        "answer": "Explanation: A set of entities of same type that share same properties or attributes is called an Entity Set.",
        "options": [
            "Entity Set",
            "Attribute Set",
            "Relation Set",
            "Entity Model"
        ]
    }
]